It’s a great pleasure that from all over the world
È un grande piacere che persone di tutto il mondo
people have gathered to worship Shiva.
si siano riunite per venerare Shiva.
Actually we should say it is Sadashiva that we are going to worship today.
In realtà dovremmo dire che è Sadashiva che adoreremo oggi.
As you know the difference between Sadashiva and Shri Shiva.
Voi sapete la differenza tra Sadashiva e Shri Shiva.
Sadashiva is the God Almighty
Sadashiva è Dio Onnipotente
and He is a witness of the play of the Primordial Mother.
ed è il testimone del gioco della Madre Primordiale.
The combination between Sadashiva and the Primordial Mother Adi Shakti
La combinazione fra Sadashiva e la Madre Primordiale Adi Shakti
is just like a moon and the moonlight or the sun or the sunlight.
è proprio come la luna e il suo chiarore o il sole e il suo splendore.
We cannot understand such relationship in human being, among human marriages
Noi non possiamo comprendere una relazione di questo genere negli esseri umani,
So whatever the Adi Shakti’s creating,
Qualsiasi cosa l’Adi Shakti crei
which is the desire of Sadashiva, is being witnessed by Him.
secondo il desiderio di Sadashiva, è testimoniata da Lui.
And when He is watching this creation
E quando Egli guarda questa creazione,
He is witnessing all of it into all details.
la osserva interamente, in ogni dettaglio.
He witnesses the whole universe
Egli testimonia l’intero universo
and He also witnesses this Mother Earth,
e testimonia anche questa Madre Terra,
all the creation that is done by the Adi Shakti.
tutta la creazione generata dall’Adi Shakti.
His power is of witnessing
Il Suo potere è quello della testimonianza,
and the power of Adi Shakti
e il potere dell’Adi Shakti
is this all pervading power of love.
è questo onnipervadente potere di amore.
So the God Almighty, the Father, the Primordial Father, we can say,
Dunque Dio Onnipotente, il Padre, il Padre Primordiale, diciamo,
expresses His desire, His Iccha Shakti as the Primordial Mother
esprime il Suo desiderio, il Suo Iccha shakti come Madre Primordiale,
and She expresses Her power as love.
e Lei esprime il proprio potere come amore.
So the relationship between the two is extremely
Pertanto la relazione fra i due è di intensa
understanding, very deep,
comprensione, molto profonda.
and whatever She‘s creating,
E qualsiasi cosa Lei crei,
if She finds, if He finds there is some problem
se Lui scopre che vi sono problemi
or there are people, human beings specially
o persone – soprattutto esseri umani –
who are trying to obstruct Her work, or even the Gods
che cercano di ostacolare il lavoro di Lei, o anche gli dèi –
who are not the deities are trying to express their egos,
che non sono le deità - che cercano di manifestare il proprio ego,
He is the one who brings forth their destruction.
Egli ne provoca la distruzione.
So He is the one who is responsible for the destructive power.
Dunque è responsabile del potere distruttivo.
He is reflected in the hearts of human beings,
Egli è riflesso nel cuore degli esseri umani;
among all the creations He pulsates.
pulsa in tutte le creazioni.
But that pulses, pulsation is the energy of the Primordial Mother.
Ma quella pulsazione è l’energia della Madre Primordiale.
And He can destroy anything that goes against the plans of the Adi Shakti.
E Lui può distruggere qualsiasi cosa si opponga ai piani dell’Adi Shakti.
Adi Shakti is love, She forgives and She loves.
L’Adi Shakti è amore, Lei perdona e ama.
She loves Her creation. She wants the creation to prosper,
Ama la propria creazione. Desidera che la creazione prosperi,
to go up to the same level for which it was created.
raggiunga proprio quel livello per cui è stata creata.
She wants human beings to go to that level where
Vuole che gli esseri umani raggiungano un livello tale
they enter into the Kingdom of God, Kingdom of Sadashiva
da entrare nel regno di Dio, nel regno di Sadashiva,
where there is bliss, there is forgiveness, there’s joy.
dove c’è beatitudine, c’è perdono, c’è gioia.
All this is only possible if you have seeking,
Tutto questo è possibile soltanto se si ha il senso della ricerca,
that you have also a innate desire to be there.
per cui si ha un desiderio innato di essere lì.
This desire within us is reflected as the reflection of the Primordial Mother.
Questo desiderio in noi si manifesta come riflesso della Madre Primordiale.